Paul Fung Cartoons
Paul Fung Cartoons
1930-1932
Fung, Paul, 1897-1944
2 linear ft.
46 original cartoons from the newspaper comic strip Dumb Dora and 4 original cartoons from the newspaper comic strip When Mother Was a Girl.
2652435
Biographical History
Paul Fung (1897-1944) was an American cartoonist. He worked on a number of newspaper comic strips during his career but is most known for the work he did as Chic Young's successor on Dumb Dora (1930-1932) and as an assistant to Cliff Sterrett on Polly and Her Pals (late 1930s).
Born in Seattle in 1897, Paul Fung was educated in the U.S. and China, where his Baptist minister father, the Rev. Fung Chak, sent him to study traditional Chinese art. In 1916, he started his newspaper career doing sports cartoons for the Seattle Post-Intelligencer. Fung's first original comic strip appeared a few months later, Innocent Hing, but it was short lived. After working as an assistant on Billy DeBeck's Barney Google in the early 1920s, Fung went on to crank out a variety of quality, but short-lived comic strips—A Guy from Grand Rapids, Bughouse Fables, Gus and Gussie. In April of 1930, Fung inherited Dumb Dora and its topper panel When Mother Was a Girl from creator Chic Young, who had left the strip to launch Blondie. Fung continued on Dumb Dora for a few years, passing it on to Bil Dwyer in 1932. Subsequently, Fung worked as an assistant on Cliff Sterrett's Polly and Her Pals in the late 1930s. The Dumb Dora comic strip ceased newspaper publication in 1934, but Fung brought Dora back in the early 1940s as part of an ad campaign for Shredded Ralston cereal. Paul Fung died in 1944. His son is the noted cartoonist Paul Fung, Jr.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Paul Fung Cartoons collection contains 36 original daily cartoons and 10 original Sunday cartoons from the newspaper comic strip Dumb Dora (1930, 1932). The Sunday version is complete in 2 panels, so note that some of our holdings are partial (see Inventory for details). The collection also contains 4 original cartoons from the topper strip When Mother Was a Girl, a companion to the Dumb Dora Sunday feature (1930).
Arrangement of the Collection
Cartoons are arranged by title in chronological order (daily and Sunday cartoons are foldered separately).
Related Material
See the
Chic Young Cartoons
collection and the
Bil Dwyer Cartoons
collection for additional material related to these comic strips. Please refer to for a complete listing of the cartoonist collections at the.
Subject and Genre Headings
Fung, Paul, 1897-1944.; King Features Syndicate.; Dumb Dora (comic strip); When mother was a girl (comic strip); Art -- Cartoonists; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Comic books, strips, etc. -- United States.; Cartoons (humorous images); Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Kenneth Rendell, 1968.
Inventory
- Dumb Dora, 46
  - Daily cartoons, 1932; 36; (blue pencil, pen and ink on illustration board, dimensions vary approx. 6 x 23 in. to 7 ¼ x 23 in.)
    - March 28, 1932 (Box 1)
    - March 29, 1932 (Box 1)
    - March 30, 1932 (Box 1)
    - March 31, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 1, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 2, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 4, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 5, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 6, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 7, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 8, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 9, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 11, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 12, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 13, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 14, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 15, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 16, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 18, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 19, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 20, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 21, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 22, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 23, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 25, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 26, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 27, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 28, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 29, 1932 (Box 1)
    - April 30, 1932 (Box 1)
    - May 2, 1932 (Box 1)
    - May 3, 1932 (Box 1)
    - May 4, 1932 (Box 1)
    - May 5, 1932 (Box 1)
    - May 6, 1932 (Box 1)
    - May 7, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Sunday cartoons, 1930, 1932; 10; (traces of graphite, blue pencil, pen and ink on illustration board, dimensions vary)
    - June 15, 1930, (partial/1 of 2 pieces)(8 x 23 in.) (Box 1)
    - July 20, 1930, (partial/1 of 2 pieces)(11 ¼ x 23 in.) (Box 1)
    - August 10, 1930, (partial/1 of 2 pieces)(7 ¾ x 23 in.) (Box 1)
    - August 17, 1930, (complete/2 of 2 pieces)(19 x 23 in.) (Box 1)
    - September 7, 1930, (complete/2 of 2 pieces)(17 ¼ x 23 in.) (Box 1)
    - November 16, 1930, (complete/2 of 2 pieces)(19 ¼ x 23 in.) (Box 1)
    - November 23, 1930, (partial/1 of 2 pieces)(11 ¼ x 23 in.) (Box 1)
    - May 8, 1932, (complete/2 of 2 pieces)(19 ½ x 23 in.) (Box 1)
    - May 15, 1932, (complete/2 of 2 pieces)(19 ¼ x 23 in.) (Box 1)
    - May 22, 1932, (complete/2 of 2 pieces)(19 ½ x 23 in.) (Box 1)
- When Mother Was a Girl, 4
  - Sunday cartoons, 1930, 1932; (traces of graphite, pasteovers, pen and ink on illustration board, approx. 10 x 23 in.)
    - August 17, 1930 (Box 1)
    - September 7, 1930 (Box 1)
    - May 8, 1932 (Box 1)
    - May 22, 1932 (Box 1)